Eason Chang

(張楹翔, Yin-Hsiang Chang)

in linkedin.com/in/easonchang101
github.com/Kamigami55

easonchang.com

eason@easonchang.com

Summary

Immersed in programming for 10+ years, including 6+ years of self-learning in web development.

Trained to be an expeditious learner and creator by competing in 10+ hackathons, and making 5+ side projects.

3+ years of frontend working experience in startup and corporate, constructed 6+ products from scratch.

Experience

Sr. Software Engineer / <u>Trend Micro</u> / 2022.01 - Present Software Engineer / <u>Trend Micro</u> / 2021.03 - 2021.12

- Rewrote legacy news site, boosted performance score from 20 to 95, search engine impression increased by 200%, improved user experience and developer experience
- Extracted UI modules into Web Component, reduced maintaining effort by 60%, used by 5+ teams
- Introduced Storybook and snapshot testing technique to frontend team

Frontend Engineer / GDP Inc. / 2018.10 - 2020.10

- Agilely built up 5 FinTech products using React.js, boosting the company to reach product-market-fit.
- Responsible for various SPA websites, Hybrid APP, and RWD campaign pages.

Education

B.S. in Computer Science / National Chiao Tung University / 2015 - 2020

Skills

Programming Language: JavaScript, Python, C/C++, PHP

Frontend technique: React.js, Next.js, Tailwind CSS, Material-UI, GraphQL, Node.js, jQuery, WordPress, HTML, CSS, SASS

Frontend expertise: Performance tuning, SEO, GA/GTM

Software quality: Storybook, Testing(Jest, Cypress), Micro Frontend

Side Projects

<u>Product Hunt Today</u>: A Twitter bot that tweets trending Product Hunt products every day in a short video Remotion / API Integration / Github Actions

<u>TaiKer Map</u>: Tourism map editing tool, select scenic spots, map style, and export to image Next.js / TailwindCSS / Google Map API / TDX API

<u>InventoryOS</u>: Inventory management system using computer vision with hardware, desktop & web interface RaspberryPI / Ruby on Rails / SQLite / OpenCV / Arduino